HISHIGATA CLINIC
菱形医院
Welcome to the white sands of Omoto Beach
欢迎来到万年青的
Dive deep below
从遥远的海底往下游
Watch the schools of fish swim
迷路的鲸鱼就在眼前
Is that a person or Hiruko?
如果看到人形 那就是蛭子大人
I'm sorry, Hizuru. I said I wanted to meet your friends.
抱歉 飞鹤 明明是我说 要见见你的朋友
But when they came…
可他们真的来了我又…
You don't need to do anything you don't want to.
没必要做自己不想做的事
I just like being with you.
我果然只要有飞鹤在就够了
You're not like the others.
飞鹤和别人不一样
Me? Different?
不一样？我吗
People run when they see me, but you ran towards me instead.
大家看到我都吓得跑掉 你不但没跑 还追过来了吧
There was a way to go upstairs of the old clinic 14 years ago.
旧医院楼的二楼 在14年前还是能上来的啊
Rumor has it that there's a ghost in the old clinic.
旧医院楼的鬼在岛上都传开了
That's why I'm told not to meet you.
所以他让我别再像这样和你见面
By who?
谁说的
Shide!
四手大人
TO BE/NOT TO BE
《第14集 生存还是毁灭》
Shide? Who's that?
四手大人 那是谁
I'm not supposed to say, but I guess I can tell you a little.
这本来是秘密 但如果是飞鹤的话 我可以稍微告诉你一些
Shide is always with greed so he's got four arms!
四手大人是个特别贪心的人 所以他有四条胳膊哦
Four arms?
四条胳膊？四手…
"Shide" as in "four arms…" "paper streamer…"
四手 还是纸垂？
That's the four-arm monster!
是那个有四条胳膊的家伙
Ah, right. I brought it.
-对了 我带来了 -什么
Here.
给
Wow!
卡尔门糖果
This is it! Thanks, Hizuru. I was wondering how it tasted.
就是这个 谢谢你 飞鹤 我一直很想知道是什么味道
I'll be the mom!
那我来当妈妈
I'll be the sister.
那我是姐姐
This must be another day.
又切换到另一天了吗
Shinpei, is she really Heine?
慎平 那孩子真的是那个波稻吗
I don't know. But let's watch this memory to the end.
不知道 继续看下去吧 这段记忆的结局…
What's wrong, Hizuru?
你怎么了 飞鹤
I cut my finger.
切到手指了
Are you okay? Show me.
没事吧？我看看
Oh. Hey.
喂 那个…
Heine? That tickles.
波稻？很痒
I hate being so tired. I hate it.
不喜欢饿肚子 不喜欢
I hate it.
不喜欢
You don't look well. Do you eat anything besides what I bring?
你最近气色很差 除了我带的零食 你要再吃点别的
Heine?
波稻？
So many died of hunger.
好多人都饿死了
Adults died, and we couldn't catch fish.
大人死了 鱼也捕不到了
In the summer,
到了夏天 妈妈 爸爸
Hizuru?
飞鹤
My shadow…
影子也…
Stroke my shadow too.
也摸摸我的影子吧
Please.
快
Your hand is so warm.
飞鹤的手好温暖
You can tell from the shadow?
影子可以感受到吗
Yeah.
嗯
I'll bring more food next time.
下次我会带多点吃的过来
Thank you, Hizuru.
谢谢你 飞鹤
You're my friend forever.
要永远和我做好朋友哦
It's summer.
变成夏天了
Hey.
喂
Are you the Minakata girl? What are you doing here?
你是南方家的女儿吧？ 在这树丛里做什么
Walking.
在走路
I can see that.
我知道
This place is dangerous. There are snakes.
我是想告诉你这里很危险 这一带有蝮蛇出没
Then why would you be safe?
那你为什么来这里 不会出事吗
I'm not.
怎么可能
That's why I'm working here.
遇到蛇当然会出事 所以我才会在这里驱蛇
You're in the way. At least use the path.
别影响我工作 要走就走山道
What? Snacks?
什么 零食吗
Yeah. She just bought a bunch. Aren't you having a party?
嗯 刚才买了一大袋 你们今天要聚会吧？
Yes, but she hasn't come back from Koba Mart.
对 可是她说了要来小早超市这里 出门后就一直没回来
What? She said she was sharing with a friend. So it wasn't you guys?
奇怪 她说要和朋友一起吃的 难道不是指朝子你们吗
What?
什么
Koba, she really said that?
你说的是真的吗 小早
-Mt. Takanosu!
-鹰巢山
Sis!
姐姐
I hope she has water.
不知道姐姐带水了没
What if she passed out somewhere?
会不会是在哪里晕倒了
She even forgets to breathe when she gets too focused.
毕竟是精神一集中 连呼吸都能忘记的人
What? Who was that?
什么 有人…
A red kimono? Who is that?
红色和服？是谁
I have a bad feeling. Is it that day?
我有不好的预感 这一天难道就是…
Is this the friend Sis told us about?
该不会是姐姐说的那个朋友
Hey.
你好
No, Ryunosuke. Don't go!
不行 龙之介先生 不能过去
Are you okay? Do you feel sick?
你没事吧？不舒服吗
Ms. Nagumo!
南云老师
Is someone there?
谁在那里吗
What? Did she hear me?
什么 她听到了我的声音？
Just my imagination?
幻听吗
"Ms. Nagumo"?
好像听到了什么“南云老师”？
Oh, no. She can't hear me anymore.
不行 她听不到了
What was that light?
怎么回事 刚才那道光…
Ryunosuke…
龙之介
Why, Heine?
为什么 波稻
Did you do this?
是你干的吗
Hizuru…
飞鹤
N-No…
不是的
Not me.
不是我
An eye? It's Heine's right eye!
眼球？是波稻的右眼
Was that…
刚刚那个难道是…
It hurts…
好疼
It hurts!
好疼啊
Ryunosuke?
龙之介
Why? Why did this happen?
为什么 为什么会这样
Heine!
波稻
You trash.
野生的影子
Who? Who are those guys?
是谁啊 这家伙是谁啊
Here. Go on.
快 去吧
Mr. Hunter.
猎人
The hell is this?
这是什么
What the…
到底是…
Watch out! Stay away!
危险 别过来
Me? I-It can't be.
是我？怎么可能
Sis…
姐姐
No way!
不会吧
What are you?
你是什么人
What the heck? Are they immortal?
不可能 那些家伙是不死之身吗
So there you are…
原来你在这里
I was looking for you…
我一直在找你
Hey!
喂
Sis, I got enough water for you too.
饮料也买了姐姐的那份
Today is our birthday, Sis.
今天是我们的生日 姐姐
He's inside Hizuru.
他在飞鹤小姐的体内
Heine released both the shadow's physical skills and Ryunosuke's data.
影子的身体能力
So it's Ryunosuke who is moving Ms. Nagumo right now.
那现在操控老师身体的是龙之介？
What was that?
什么 刚才那是？
Sorry, Sis. I might've dislocated your shoulder.
抱歉 姐姐 肩膀好像脱臼了
Hey! Are you okay?
喂 你没事吧？
Stay with me! Hey!
坚持住 喂
HIZURU ASAKO
飞鹤 朝子
Since we're friends, I'll let you go this once.
毕竟是朋友 我就放过你一次
The next time we meet… I'll kill you.
下次见面 我会杀了你
You… You came back.
你回来了吗
This is before we went inside Koba Mart.
这是在闯入小早超市之前的时间
No, don't.
不行 老师
Don't go in.
中止闯入计划
Ushioh hit Shinpei's neck and looped.
潮砍掉了慎平的脑袋 进入循环了
Papa, what time is it?
爸爸 现在几点
Well, it's six o'clock.
我看看 刚过下午6点
Last time, it was before the funeral. The starting point is getting later.
上次是在葬礼的捡骨仪式前开始的 起点推迟了？
Maybe it's starting later because Shinpei's power is getting weaker.
循环的起点推迟 也许是因为 慎平的力量变弱了
I see. Each time he dies,
嗯 可以观测到的时间范围 每死一次就会变窄一点
This is a good discovery.
真是个很不错的发现
Then let him do what he said and make him loop over and over…
就让他按自己说的一遍一遍去循环吧
until he reaches his limit.
直到超出时间范围
So we kill Shinpei until he can't loop anymore,
你是说他循环一次 我们就杀他一次 直到他再也无法循环
then he'll die for good?
迎来他真正的死亡吗
Exactly. Let him use up his life. It's easier than capturing him alive.
没错 耗光他的生命 这比活捉他要简单
Right, Shide?
对吧 四手？
Yes.
是的
Asako. Seconds, please.
朝子 麻烦再来一碗
ONE HOUR LATER
一小时后
Are you hungry? I brought you this.
老师 你饿了吗 不介意的话 就吃这个吧
You are a strange man. You cook at a time like this.
你真是个奇怪的人 这种时候还有心思做料理
On that day, Ryunosuke entered you.
那一天 龙之介先生 进入了老师的体内对吧？
I was surprised at first, but I got used to it in time.
我一开始也很吃惊 后来慢慢习惯了
Ryunosuke is strong like Ushioh, and you've saved me many times.
龙之介先生和潮一样都很强 多亏了老师 我们被救了好几次
I would prefer to fight myself. I don't want to bring out Ryunosuke.
如果可以的话 我希望由我来战斗 其实我并不想把龙之介叫到这里来
You care for your brother, don't you?
老师很珍爱弟弟啊
Why do you think so?
为什么这么说
I have a sister too, so I understand.
我也有个妹妹 所以多少能理解你的感受
You don't want Ryunosuke to fight shadows and suffer again.
老师不想让龙之介先生与影子交战 是怕他再次想起那可怕的经历吧
You're overthinking it.
你俯瞰过头了
Am I?
是吗
I'm only looking after myself.
我是为了我自己
If he fought with all his power, my body would shatter into pieces.
那家伙如果使出全力战斗 我的身体会被撕碎的
On that day, when my shoulder was dislocated and my ankle was sprained,
那时候也是 肩膀脱臼 腿部扭伤
I was in bed unable to move for five days.
全身肌肉疼痛 连续四五天都完全动不了
What a royal pain, right?
谁能受得了
Oh, did you not like spicy food?
您是吃不了辣吗
No, this is great. It reminds me of eating at Kofune.
不 很好吃 是以前在小舟吃过的味道
Every 22nd, Mio's shadow was at Kofune, but tonight, she'll likely come here.
虽然前几次的22日的夜晚 影子泠都会去西餐厅小舟
Shadow Mioh pretty much ignores Mio.
影子泠基本上无视真正的泠
She has an order that overrules her instinct to kill her original.
比起遵从影子的本能杀死原型 她优先遵从上面的命令
It's an order from Heine.
也就是波稻的命令
We can use that to our advantage.
所以我们将计就计
Yes.
嗯
With this mark, can Heine know my location too?
这个印记会把我的位置透露给波稻吗
We'll find out. Since the enemy loops too, we must move quickly.
这一点接下来也就知道了
If Ushioh shares her memories, others will feel like they looped.
只要潮把记忆分享给大家 就相当于大家也经历了循环
We will attack at full combat capability from the very beginning.
在初期就能用最大战力去迎击
Sorry I called you a monster.
对不起 我还说你是怪物
You were fighting as hard as you could.
姐姐明明一直在拼命战斗
Oh, at the summer festival? No worries. I am sort of a monster.
你说夏日庆典的时候吗 没事啦 本来也是像怪物一样啊
I'm not upset at…
我没往心里去…
I thought I'd never see you again!
我还以为再也见不到你了
Mio, don't cry so much.
泠 不用哭成这样啦
Sis, let me fight. I can't just watch you two protect me.
姐姐 我也要战斗 我不想总是 被小慎和姐姐保护
Mio, we brought you here to keep you safe.
泠 我们把你带来这里 是为了你的安全着想
Shinpei, I'm ready to fight back.
我不想一直当被欺压的一方
Alain's not picking up. He's usually home by now.
没接电话啊 艾伦 前几次的这个时候已经到家了
Shinpei?
慎平？
Are you okay?
你没事吧？
Yes, I'm just a bit nervous. Do I have to do this?
没 只是有点紧张 我们真的要这么做吗
A mission needs a leader. Everyone wants to hear from you.
作战需要一个领导者 大家都想听你说几句
It's gotta be you, Shinpei!
慎平你是最合适的啦
If it weren't for your powers, none of us would be here like this.
要是没有慎平的力量 大家也不会像这样聚集在一起
Okay… Well…
那我就…那个…
I have always stepped back to look at things.
我从小就有俯瞰的习惯
It felt like another me was looking from high above and thinking.
那种感觉就像有另一个自己 从高处看着自己 思考问题
I was able to see myself amidst my surroundings.
就能全面看到自己所处的位置 和周围的情况等等
Even if I messed up, it didn't feel personal.
就算失败了 也好像失败的人不是自己
I thought I was being smart by living like that.
我本以为这样做就能过得很好
But after Ushio died, I'm just left with regrets.
可是潮死后 我只有后悔的份
I should've at least called her. I could've come home for New Years.
为什么一个电话都没打给过她 为什么过年都不回来看看她
I should've made her that curry one last time.
要是我离开的前一天 我做了她让我做的咖喱该有多好
I thought I saw everything, but I missed that.
明明一直在俯瞰 却什么都没做到
I've made so many mistakes.
我一直在犯错
It hurts me to regret things I can't fix.
如今才来后悔已经无法挽回的事情 真的很痛苦
I'll probably have regrets again, but I don't want to ever feel like this.
今后我再也不想后悔了 虽然不太可能
So I will avoid doing anything that I might regret.
所以我决定 只要有一点 可能会后悔的苗头 我就会避开
I decided to run away from it.
拼尽全力去逃避
Run away?
你要逃避吗
But that doesn't mean I don't have to do anything.
可是这样的话 就没有多少不做的选择了
If I'm going to have regrets, I will do something about it.
就算是不想做的事 一想到之后可能会后悔
That's how I feel now.
现在是的 我就是这么想的
In other words, even if I fail and end up dead…
总而言之 那个… 就算最后失败了 死了
I want to think that I gave my whole life for this.
我也希望自己是用尽生命努力过了
You saw that Ushio fought alone with shadows before she died.
大家应该都看到了 潮在生前 曾经暗中与影子战斗
She lost her life, trying to save Shiori.
为了救诗织失去了生命
She must've been truly disappointed.
她应该会觉得很不甘心 非常不甘心
I will finish what she started.
我会继承她的遗志
I won't let the end of that summer festival repeat itself.
不会让那场夏日庆典的悲剧重演
If we all work together, I believe we will be successful,
我相信大家齐心协力一定能做到
but don't take my word for it.
我不会这么说
No, huh?
不会这么说？
I can't guarantee your lives. I don't know if we will win this fight.
我无法保证大家的安危 也不知道这场战斗能不能赢
But I'm not giving you the choice to leave either.
但我也不会说想逃的人就尽管逃吧
I know I'm being selfish, but I don't want any regrets.
这一切都是为了让我自己不后悔的 任性的想法
I'm forcing you to stay because I don't want to regret not forcing you.
我不希望因为这时候没有强迫大家 而导致事后后悔 所以我要强迫你们
Please take a weapon and fight with me.
请大家拿上武器 和我一起战斗吧
Okay. How will it come?
会从哪里出现 又是如何出现的呢
Oh, a snake.
原来是蛇
Shinpei loves the island and all of you!
慎平喜欢这座岛 也喜欢岛上的大家
He's not good with words, but Shinpei is on your side.
虽然他说话一直都很难听 但是慎平是大家的伙伴
What's wrong with taking the side of people you love?
帮助喜欢的人有什么问题吗
I'll fight!
我也要战斗
Mio?
小泠？
Me too, Shinpei!
我也加入 慎平
I'm always on your side. That never changes.
我一辈子都会是你的伙伴 这一点永远不会变
Do you know the facts?
各位 你们知道吗
Do you know how many shadows are on this island?
这座岛上有多少影子存在
We've got no chance. Even more so if Heine is looping.
从现状来看 我们根本没有胜算 而且波稻也能循环 我们更不可能赢
Shinpei is trying to get us all killed.
慎平哥想做的事情 根本就是集体自杀行为
Tokiko!
朱鹭子
That's right! Tell it to him!
就是 继续说
But… I've already died once. My life is yours now.
不过反正都死过一次了 这条命就交给你吧
What?
什么
There is no path forward without exterminating them.
除了驱逐他们 我们没有别的选择了
Darn… No…
可恶 怎么这样 可恶
Fine, let's do this! I'm a man of action! Darn it!
我知道了
Thank you, everyone.
谢谢你们
What? I'm at home.
什么 这是我家？
I'm back? I looped.
回来了？循环了吗
I… died?
死了吗 我…
When?
什么时候